It's not the fur that people are allergic to but the proteins and they shed the same proteins that all cats have.
That enzyme that people respond to as an allergen.
So when your looking into whether or not you are allergic to this kind of cat, you want to make sure to spend some time with him.
The truth is all other cats shed.
The shedding is a natural part of being a cat and in fact it's an important part of being a cat if our cat isn't shedding, that tells you that something is going on with your cat that's not right.
They maybe ill and they may need some medical attention.
For cats that do have fur, there are lots of tools that can help you reduce the shedding.
There are plenty of products like this that claim to help reduce shedding.
Usually it's a matter if they have a lot of vitamins, and omega three fatty acids.
Basically they're supplements that help maintain a high quality of skin care for the cat which helps reduce the dander because the less dry skin, which helps reduce shedding.
The other thing that's really important for your cat especially if you have a medium to long haired cat is to groom the cat properly.
This is a great tool.
This is a rake, you just rake it over the back of the cat's fur and you'd be amazed how much fur you can pull out of the coat.
I usually like to follow that up with, this is a greyhound comb, has the tines that are closer together then further apart, so you can use the tines that are further apart across the coat first and then switch over to the tines that are closer together as you pull out more fur.
If you end up with a mat, this is a mat splitter that you can use to, to gently lift the mat out.
You just want to be careful not to hurt the cat.
And then of course there's the ever important flea comb.
There's other tools, like there's all kinds of gloves like this that you can use to help just pull that fur out, pull that fur out and just expose of it.